

# Pooja Rani

#### Curriculum Vitae

# Objective

My main **research goal** is to conduct research, involving both industrial and academic collaborations, to support developers in various software engineering tasks such as program comprehension and maintenance tasks. My **research interests** are in the domain of Software Engineering (SE), human aspects of SE, empirical software engineering, Data Science (DS), Natural language processing (NLP) and Machine learning applied to SE, and Software maintenance and evolution (with particular focus on IDE improvements).

#### Education

2018 – now **Ph.D in Software Engineering**, supervised by Oscar Nierstrasz and Sebastiano Panichella, University of Bern, Switzerland.

2015 – 2017 **Masters of Engineering in Software System**, *Birla Institute of Technology and Science-Pilani*, Rajasthan, India, *CGPA – 8.53*.

2011 – 2014 **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science**, *The Institution of Engineers*, India, *CGPA* – 8.33.

2008 – 2011 **Diploma in Computer Science and Engineering**, Kalpana Chawla Goverment Polytechnic for Women, Ambala, Haryana, India, Percentage – 83.

## Work Experience

July, 2017 - Software Developer, at People Interactive Group pvt Itd. Mumbai, India.

Dec, 2017 Changing underlaying architecture and migrating code to node js framework

Jan, 2017 - Member of Technical Staff, at VMware Software India pvt Itd.Bangalore, India.

Jun, 2017 Developing a framework for automating identity access management flow

Jul, 2011 - **Software Tester**, at Samsung Research Institute, Noida, India.

July, 2014 Creating test plan, resource planning, review meetings for mobile testing

# Teaching Activities

- 2018 2021 Course Instructor, University of Bern, Bachelor & Master courses.
  - o Object-Oriented Programming: Bsc course, every Spring 2018, 2019, 2020, and 2021.
  - o Software Modeling Analysis: Msc course, Autumn 2018, and 2020.
- 2015 2016 **Teaching Assistant, BITS Pilani**, Bachelor courses.
  - o Computer Architecture: BE course, explaining verilog concepts, designing lab experi-
  - o Computer Programming: BE course, C language concepts, organizing exercises.
  - o Software Testing: ME course, designing and correcting exercises

# Supervision Activities

- 2019-2020 Msc thesis, University of Bern.
  - Supervised one master student and published the work in SANER, 2021
- 2018-2021 Bsc thesis, University of Bern & University of Zurich.

Supervised 5 bachelor students, currently writing two works

2018-2021 **Seminar projects, University of Bern**.

Supervised 3 seminar students on various topics

#### **Publications**

- JSS How to Identify Class Comment Types? A Multi-language Approach for Class Comment Classification, 2021.
- EMSE What do class comments tell us? An investigation of comment evolution and practices in Pharo Smalltalk, To appear, 2021.
- ICSE Speculative analysis for comment quality assessment, 2021.
- SANER Makar: A framework for multi-source studies based on unstructured data,
  - SCAM Two articles under review, 2021.
    - JSS A Systematic Literature Review on Comment Quality, Submission under preparation, 2021.
- SATToSE **Software Analysis using Natural Language Queries**, 2018.

#### Collaborations

- Sebastiano Panichella, Switzerland
- Nataliia Stulova, Switzerland

Alexandre Bergel, Chille

- Mohammad Ghafari, New Zealand
- Andrea Di Sorbo, Italy
- Alessandra Gorla, Spain

### Other Professional activities

- 2019-Today Board Member of CHOOSE group (Swiss group for Software Engineering
- 2018-2021 Co-reviewed papers of various international conferences and journals (SANER, TOSEM, ICSME)

# Achievements and Awards

- 2018 Best presentation award at SATTOSE, 2018
- 2014 Qualified GATE 2015 Research fellowship from MHRD(Ministry of Human Research Development), India.
- 2012 Received the youngest Employee of the year award in Samsung.
- 2011 Batch Topper Secured 1st Rank in Diploma college.
- 2007 Silver Medal Won Silver Medal in state level Taekwondo Championship, Haryana.

## References

Available on Request

## More Details

Date of Birth - 20-01-1993

Nationality - Indian

Language - English (C1), Hindi (native), German (A2.1)

Home page — https://poojaruhal.github.io/

Office page - http://scg.unibe.ch/staff/Pooja-Rani

Google Scholar - https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=2B8GcJ4AAAAJ